残酷な天使のように 少年よ 神話になれ
青い風が今 胸のドアを叩いても 私だけをただ見つめて 微笑んでるあなた
そっと触れるもの 求めることに夢中で 運命さえまだ知らない 痛い気な瞳
だけどいつか気づくでしょう その背中には
遥か未来 目指すための羽があること
残酷な天使の帝世 窓辺からやがて飛び立つ
ほとばしる熱いパッドスで 思い出を裏切るなら
この空を抱いて輝く 少年よ 神話になれ
ご視聴ありがとうございました
心の centres
ゆいっぱい部活動
あ でも あなたの歴 새로沒有
あ genugか
ご視聴ありがとうございました
あ 永遠のおかしい
You damn f-
Thanks for letting us in, Shinji.
That rainstorm came out of nowhere.
So, like, where's Misato?
She must still be asleep.
She's been working all night a lot lately.
Yeah, she's got a tough job.
Well, then, I guess we've got to be quiet so that we don't wake Misato up, right?
Well...
Shh!
Hey!
What the heck are these creeps doing in here?
Shhh!
Drying themselves?
Oh, sure. Talk about lame excuses!
Well, I'm changing in here, and if you peep, you're dead!
You stuck-up, becatistical little dude want to watch a snake changing its skin anyway!
She's sure full of herself.
Huh?
Mimi! Misato!
Did we wake you up?
Actually, I was already awake.
Thanks for asking, though.
Shinji, don't forget that we're having a harmonics test at the lab this evening.
Oh, right.
Hey, Asuka, did you hear that?
Yes, ma'am!
Huh?
Wow!
I mean, congratulations on your promotion, Misato.
Yeah, congratulations.
You're too kind.
No, ma'am. You deserved it.
Well, I'll see you guys later.
Have fun!
See ya!
So, what's up?
Did something happen to Misato?
Haven't you seen her new badge?
It's got two stripes on it now.
Two stripes means that she's been promoted to major.
Promoted?
I did. I didn't notice.
Yeah, me neither.
Neither of you noticed?
What a bunch of lame-os.
Man, don't you guys ever pay attention to that poor, hard-working woman?
Do you have any idea of how hard it must be to take care of the two of you at her age?
I guess it's a good thing that some of us still have a little human compassion.
Units 0 and 2 are both on the edge of the contamination zone.
They've reached their limit.
Unit 1 can still tolerate a little more, though, can't he?
Lower the graph depth another 0.3.
He's almost reached the contamination zone.
And he's still getting these readings?
He's just wonderful.
His harmonics and sync ratio are rapidly catching up with Asuka's.
He does have talent, doesn't he?
It's as if he was born to become a Nava pilot, isn't it?
But that's not what Shinji wants.
I know he's not really happy here.
The test has been completed.
That was excellent work, Shinji.
What do you mean?
Your harmonics value has increased by 8 points since the last test.
That's very good.
But it's still 50 points below mine.
That's true.
But 8 points in 10 days is amazing.
I don't think it's so great.
Okay, third child.
Enjoy your victory while you can.
I'll see you when you get home, jerk face.
And here's your message for Mr. Y in Tokyo, too.
And look, bud, having your first...
Oh, by the way, it's nice that you got promoted.
Thanks, Shinji.
But to tell you the truth, I'm not really all that thrilled with it.
Oh, I understand.
I'm not crazy about getting praised in public either.
Especially when it's like earlier today.
All it did was make Asuka angry.
Why does she get so pissed off?
It's so stupid.
It bothers you, doesn't it?
It does.
Well, that's because you think too much about what others think.
Congratulations!
Way to go, Misato!
Thanks, you guys.
And thank you, Toji.
No, no.
This was Kensuke's idea.
That's right, I, Kensuke Ida, am the mastermind behind this dinner.
Oh, well, then thank you, Mr. Ida.
Oh, it was no problem.
It wasn't such a big deal, really.
Hey, by the way, just what is Hikari doing here?
I invited her, Doomkopf.
Yeah?
Did you invite Rei, too?
Well, I invited her, but she's not exactly the party type, you know?
Darn, why is Kaji so late?
Kaji?
You mean that really cool-looking guy who never shaves?
Yeah.
After hanging around these dorks all day, it's nice to know what a real man is like.
Real man?
So, kiddo, is it still difficult for you to be in this kind of situation?
I'm okay.
I'm just not used to being around so many people.
Why do they have to be so nosy?
Your promotion.
That means that someone must appreciate the kind of work you've been doing, right?
Yeah, I suppose so.
That's why they're all so happy for you.
But you don't look very happy at all.
Oh, I'm happy.
But that's not the reason I do what I do.
So, why did you join now?
Oh, I don't know.
It's been a long time since I signed up, you know.
Oh, that's gotta be Kaji!
I came directly from headquarters.
We just happened to meet on the way.
A likely story.
You're not jealous, are you?
Hmm.
Absolutely not.
I'd like to give you my sincerest regards, Major Katsuragi.
I suppose I'll have to be polite to you from now on.
Hmm.
And just what does that mean?
Well, you know that Commanders Ikari and Fiyutsuki have never left Japan at the same time before.
I guess they must really feel old Katsuragi here's dependable.
My father's left Japan again?
That's right, Shinji.
He's at the South Pole.
Once this was a living continent of Antarctica.
Now it's an ocean of death.
The Pole.
Not just another name for hell.
Nevertheless, mankind has returned to this wasteland.
In the midst of death, we still live.
That's because we're under the protection of science.
Science is what makes man powerful.
That kind of self-righteous arrogance is what caused the tragedy of 15 years ago.
The second impact.
And here, before us, is the end result.
This is a far greater punishment than mankind deserved.
This is the real Dead Sea.
Yet this is a world that has been purified and purged of the original sin.
I'd rather live in a world with people, no matter how stained this.
This is the bridge.
We've just received a telex from NERV headquarters.
An Angel has been detected in orbit above the Indian Ocean.
The Angel appeared about two minutes ago.
Send recon satellite number six to that orbit.
T-minus two minutes to contact.
Target has been sighted.
Oh, it's enormous.
It's impressive, all right.
Recon six is now in range.
Commencing data search.
Commencing data transmission.
Data transmission complete.
Was that an AT field?
Yes.
A new way of using one.
Look at the size of that tidal wave.
That's an AT field impact.
It uses kinetic energy, too.
This Angel is like a huge living bomb.
At least the first blast missed and hit the ocean.
However, the second shot hit closer to land, and for the last two hours, it's been steadily
correcting its error ratio.
So it's learning to aim itself.
We detonated an N2 aerial mine on it.
No effect.
The Angel has been hiding since then.
It's coming here, isn't it?
It's a safe bet.
And if it falls on us...
Then there'll be a third Ashinoka Lake, right?
Actually, this whole area will become an extension of the Pacific Ocean.
Can we contact Commander Ikari?
It's impossible.
We can't get through the Angel's jamming.
What about the Magi?
The Magi are unanimous in recommending evacuation.
What will you do?
You're the one who's in charge of all this now.
Notify all the ministries concerned that I am issuing a special D-17 declaration.
All residents within a radius of 50 kilometers are to evacuate immediately.
Also, tell Matsushiro to back up the Magi.
Are we going to evacuate as well?
No, but it's not necessary to place everyone here at risk.
Your attention, please.
The government has announced a D-17 special declaration of emergency for this area.
All residents must evacuate to their designated locations.
Beginning with the Blocks 6 and 7, evacuate according to the directions of your district chief immediately.
The evacuation of the city is now complete.
The evacuation of all non-combatant and D-class personnel by Alarm C has been completed.
You're not really serious, are you?
Yes, I am.
You're willing to sacrifice all three Avas to satisfy your own ambitions?
The chance of success is 0.001%.
Just one in 10,000.
Well, it's not 0.001%.
I just trust the Avas.
Major Katsuragi, don't forget that I'm the one in charge now.
I have to do what I have to do.
Destroying the Angels is my duty.
Your duty?
You must be kidding.
This is to satisfy yourself, isn't it?
This is just your revenge against the Angels.
What?
You want us to catch it with our hands?
That's right.
We'll locate the Avas in an estimated drop zone.
Then, while maintaining your AT fields, you'll catch it before it hits the ground.
But what if it doesn't fall where you think it will?
Then there'll be a little boom.
But what if the Avas can't handle the impact?
We'll all be blown to the moon.
What are our chances?
I've got no idea.
Not so good, in my opinion.
If we pull this off, it'll be a miracle.
Miracles aren't something that just happened.
They're something that people make happen.
We've got to be willing to sacrifice ourselves.
I'm sorry, Aska.
We've got no other choice.
This is the best plan.
How can you call something this crazy a plan?
I suppose I can't, really.
You can refuse to do it if you wish.
I see.
So you are okay with this?
The regulations state here that you're all supposed to write out a will.
Have you done that yet?
I don't need to write one.
I'm not going to die just yet.
Neither do I.
There's no point to it.
Yeah, me neither.
Okay.
But when all of this is over, I'll treat all of you to a steak dinner, okay?
A steak dinner?
Yep.
Wow.
You won't forget, right?
I swear I won't.
A steak dinner is supposed to impress us?
Does she really think we'd go crazy just for a dumb steak dinner?
Man, the second impact generation has really got some cheap standards.
I suppose she just can't help it.
Well, that wow you made sounded pretty enthusiastic to me, Shinji.
Well, it may not mean much to us, but it still means something to her, you know?
I suppose so.
Well, let's figure out where she's going to take us.
Tokyo 3 Five Star Restaurant Directory.
You're going to be coming with us, right, First Child?
I don't think so.
Why not?
I dislike eating meat.
Angel's ECM jamming has caused us to lose track of it again.
Since it's impossible to calculate the exact location,
the Magi have estimated a probable drop zone radius from what little data we could collect.
This is it.
That's a huge area to cover!
It could drop on any of these locations?
Given the size of the target's AT field,
it could completely annihilate Nerve Headquarters simply by coming close with a near miss.
So, we'll disperse the Avis so there's one at each of these three points.
What is this dispersal based on?
A guess.
A guess?
It's women's intuition.
Her woman's intuition.
Looks like our miracle's getting further and further away.
She plays the lottery a lot, and she never wins either.
Ooh.
Hey, Asuka.
What?
Why did you become an Ava pilot?
To show the world how great I am, of course.
So, it's a way of proving that you exist?
Yeah, I guess you could say that.
Why don't you ask Wonder Girl?
I've already talked with her about it.
Hmm.
So, you've been having secret meetings.
No, it's not like that.
So, why do you do this?
I don't know.
Just what do you mean?
Are you stupid?
Uh, maybe I am.
Ah.
I suppose you really are.
20 minutes to estimated time of impact.
The rest of you can leave now.
I can take care of this situation.
Sorry.
This is our job as well.
Yeah, we can't let those kids risk their lives all by themselves.
Don't worry about the children.
No matter how badly the Avas might get damaged, their AT fields will protect them.
Actually, the safest place to be right now is inside the Ava.
The other day, you wanted to know why I really joined Nerve.
It began with my father.
He lived for his work, to the exclusion of everything else.
I was never able to forgive him for that.
In fact, at times, I even hated him.
It sounds like my father.
He never really took care of me or my mother.
His friends always said that he was too sensitive and fragile.
But the truth was, he was just a weak person.
He didn't want to face reality.
So avoiding his family was easier than dealing with it.
When my mother decided to divorce him, I was actually happy.
I was so sick of hearing her cry herself to sleep.
And when my dad got upset about it, I actually laughed at him because I thought he got what he deserved.
But then he sacrificed himself to save my life during this second impact.
But then I didn't know whether I hated him or loved him.
The only thing that was clear to me was that I wanted to destroy the angels who had caused the second impact.
And that's why I joined Nerve.
It might be that I still hate him and just want to avenge my father so that I can finally free myself from him.
It's the only way I can escape.
I mustn't run away.
I won't.
I won't run away.
The target has been sighted.
Maximum magnification.
Distance, approximately 25,000.
The falling angel's been sighted.
All Avas, get on your marks.
We can only give you a rough estimated trajectory based upon optical observations.
The magi will guide you until the estimated distance is 10,000 meters.
After that, you'll have to use your own judgment.
Remember, I'm placing my trust in you.
The angel is approaching.
Distance, 20,000.
Right.
Begin the operation.
Here we go.
Let's move out!
Distance, 12,000.
Spreading A.T. field!
Unit 2, expand your field!
I'm already doing it!
Do it now!
Ain't this!
More!
Hmm.
Our wireless communications have been restored.
We're receiving a transmission from Commander Ikari in Antarctica.
Connect him, please.
Yes, ma'am.
I apologize, sir.
Because of my irresponsible judgment, Unit 1 has incurred some damage.
I take full responsibility for this, sir.
No. Destroying angels is an Ava's purpose.
It was fortunate that the amount of damage done was minimal.
Excellent work, Major Katsuragi.
Thank you, Commander.
And on that subject, is the pilot of Unit 1 there?
Yes.
I've just read the report. Good work, Shinji.
Yes, sir.
Now, Major Katsuragi, I'll leave the handling of the rest of this in your hands.
The next station is New Mianoshita. New Mianoshita. The door will open on the left side of the next station.
So, now you're going to have to fulfill your promise.
Well, of course I will.
I went and pulled some large bills for my account so that I could cover everything.
Of course, now I'm broke.
A ramen place?
Well, we know how poor you are, Misato.
This will be fine.
And since there's no meat, Wonder Girl will be joining us.
One garlic ramen with no roast pork.
I'll have shark spin ramen with roast pork.
Super size it!
There you go.
Say, Misato.
Yeah?
I think I finally understood the good part about being praised by someone when I heard my father's words today.
And I also realized that the reason I pilot my Ava is to hear those words from him.
Now, wait a second.
That's why you're a pilot?
Jeez, you really are an idiot.
You really are an idiot?
In another world, darling kiss me
Fill my heart with some
And let me sing forever more
You are all I know
For all I worship and I do
In another world, please be true
In another world, I love you
The Magi, the trio of supercomputers
that command all of Nerve headquarters are under attack
As problems mount and central dogma is invaded
Nerve is forced to accept a course of self-destruction
It all happens in the next episode
Angel Invasion